So the Conservative Party I think just
died. So Cammy Benock who is the current
leader of the Conservative Party who
isn't doing particularly well has just
sacked Robert Genrich widely seen to be
the person who was basically just
waiting for her to resign or have a
leadership challenge so that he could
take over. Effectively she said that
there was clear and irrefutable evidence
that he was planning to defect to the
Reform Party led by Nigel Farage. Um,
and I think this might be the worst bit
of political strategy that Kemi Bnock
could have done here and might have just
ended the Conservatives for good. So,
there had long been rumors that Genrich,
who had been on a long march to the
right, might have defected to reform.
However, going from a position where he
was effectively leader and waiting of
the Conservative Party, which is sort of
the most successful uh political party
in modern political history, going from
a position where he was basically
waiting to walk into the leadership role
of that party and then defecting to
reform would have looked a bit weak and
a little bit grubby, I think. Whereas
her sacking him and removing the whip
and therefore allowing him to go, "Well,
I've been kicked out. I'm moving to
reform." Potentially makes for a much
more powerful narrative. The broader
risk is that it essentially says to any
other Conservative MPs who have been
thinking about defecting, well, if we
find out there's any chance you're going
to, we're going to sack you. You might
as well jump. Now, I made a video way
back uh when the Conservative Party was
still in power in the UK and were a
little bit on the ropes, wondering
whether it might be the end of the party
for good. And I remember in the comments
there being some pretty reasonable
questions over whether this always seems
to be the case when a party is on the
way out. Most political parties spend
some time in the wilderness and come
back. But I think this could be the end
of one of the most successful political
parties in modern political history.